Uma Rathore





Mississauga, ON | Cell: (+1) 437-988-0820 | Mail: umarathore@yahoo.com

PROFILE

Overall 5+ years of IT experience. Around 3 years in Business Process Management and 2+ years in Application Support and maintenance. Branched out of IT and started a family. Keen on transitioning back into the workforce as a Python Developer in a best fit role, having 6 months of experience in Python Programming. Enthusiastic about coding and Machine Learning.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frameworks

- Flask
- ITIL
- ETOM

Version Control

Github

Web Development tools

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript

Computer Languages

Python 3.9

Machine Learning

- Supervised Learning
- Unsupervised Learning
- Reinforcement

Content Management

- Documentum
- First Doc Applications
- Syncplicity

Developer environments

- PyCharm
- Jupyter Notebooks
- VS Code
- Sublime Text
- VB Macros

Libraries

- Scikit-learn
- Pandas
- NumPy
- Matplotlib

BPM Tools

- ARIS Business Designer
- ARIS Business Architect
- ARIS Publisher
- SAP Solution Manager
- BonitaSoft
- MS Visio

Application Support Tools

Remedy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Python Developer

Continuing Education, Mississauga, ON/ Dec 2020 - June 2021

- Complete Python Developer in 2021 Zero to Mastery course certified by Udemy.
- Developer Environments (PyCharm, Jupyter Notebooks, VS Code, Sublime Text)
- Designed and Developed a Portfolio website using the Flask framework.
- Overview of Machine Learning and Data Science.
- Daily contributor to leetcode and hands on working with github.
- Iris Flower Data Set project: followed steps of Machine Learning: Data gathering imported dataset from sklearn library, model selection Supervised classification data model, analysis of model and improvement find best value of k to increase accuracy score.
- Soccer Player project: data gathering imported dataset from kraggle.com (Fifa 2016 football team players), data cleaning - Calculation of their difference in Value and Earning
- Web Warehouse data collection from server log files, log cleaning, data transformation, data representation for analysis.

Stay-at-Home Mother

Leave of Absence to start a family, Houston, Texas/ May 2016 - Dec 2020

 Took a break from my job and started a family. Raised one kid, managed a family of 3 and organised a household. Kid is now 4 years old. Now eager to return to pursuing a full-time career.

Software Engineering Sr. Analyst

Accenture Solution Private Limited, Pune, Maharashtra / Jan 2014 - May 2016

- Requirement gathering from client users, documented & Implemented/customized process flows in business process management software ARIS(Architecture of Integrated Information System).
- Researching enhanced processes for ARIS, performed & evaluated proof of concepts, created & implemented the technical design in Non-prod & Production environments, performed test & capture test results.
- Planned, Designed, and Implemented Change requests and Minor enhancements as per Business Requests for ARIS and First Doc Applications.
- Change Management, Problem Management, Knowledge Management, SLA, Service Restoration Calls, Escalation calls, and DHC (Daily Health Check) Meeting, etc.
- Worked on Content Management for User Access Management, business process workflows, document security, and document lifecycle management.
- Daily, Weekly & Monthly operational, and monitoring tasks. Daily health check report for Storage, repositories, FirstDoc applications, ARIS application, infrastructure, and integrated systems.
- Handled Remedy tickets/Service Requests to resolve the business user-related issues/gueries.
- Complete all appropriate documentation required by the Support team that will maintain the application.
- Administered, upgraded, performed tuned, troubleshot, developed maintenance procedures.
- Led the teams for ARIS and Syncplicity applications. Major role in bringing various stakeholders, vendors, users
 and SMEs on the same platform and resolving the issues. Task allocation and coordination with Resources
 handling Level 1.5 and Level 2 support activities.

Senior Process Designer

Tech Mahindra Limited, Mumbai, Maharashtra / Jan 2011 - Jan 2014

- Capture business requirements and investigate business processes and business needs to resolve underlying
 pain areas in existing Business Processes. Lead the team of Process Designers to meet project coordination
 requirements between multiple lines of businesses.
- Doing ARIS modeling of Processes including EPC (Event Process Chain Diagram) and FAD (Function Allocation Diagram) for different retail tracks like PLAN, BUY, MOVE, SELL, FINANCE, HR, DSS, IT and Oil and Gas tracks like Human Capital Management, Procurement, and Contracting, Logistics, RFM, etc.
- Modeled WBDS (Work Break-Down Structures), Org Charts (Organization Charts), Capability Models, Team
 Architectures. Understanding End-to-End Business Processes of various Domains of Retail like Procure to Pay,
 Order to Cash, etc.
- Automation of process status Tracker using VBA macros.
- Prototype Research & Evaluation for Business Reports. Enhancement of ARIS Business Architect Module to
 meet Client's requirements and provide solutions as necessary. Develop Java Scripts for report customization to
 achieve enhanced functionality and productivity.
- Prepare different ARIS Reports including Model Status, Process Interface Dependency, Object Summary, and High-Level VACD (Value Added Chain Diagram) using ARIS Scripts.
- ARIS Software Administration such as Users & Access management, Creation & implementation of rules for custom user interface, Process model versioning, Database creation & reorganization, ARIS maintenance, Microsoft Visio objects conversion into ARIS objects.
- Integration of ARIS (Architecture of Integrated Information System) and SAP environments through SAP Solution Manager. Synchronization and reverse synchronization of ARIS Business Process objects in SolMan. Plan, Design, Implementation, execution of test cases, and documentation of test results.
- Business Process Automation using BONITASOFT software. Design, develop & troubleshoot the workflows to improve process efficiency and productivity.

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATIONS

WORK ELIGIBILITY

Canada: Permanent Resident

Master of Computer Application (2010)

Rajiv Gandhi Technical Univ., India

ITIL V3 Foundation - organization level

India: Citizen

Bachelor of Computer Science (2007)

Barkatullah University, India